kevinpayravi@gmail.com

www.kevinpayravi.com

www.github.com/KevinPayravi

(330) 554 - 3397

## Objective

Currently a second-year college student in Computer Science & Engineering at The Ohio State University with experience in software and web development, graphic design, and social media management. I am passionate and interested in contributing to an internship involving software and web development while expanding my experience in these areas.

#### Education

#### College of Engineering, The Ohio State University

Fall 2013 - May 2017 (expected)

Pursuing B.S.E. in Computer Science & Engineering
Member of Big Data and Analytics and Open Source Club
Software I & II (CSE 2221 & 2231) Foundations I (CSE 2321) Computing Ethics (PHILOS 1337)

# Technical Experience & Schoolwork

Platforms - Windows, Linux, OS X, Android, Arduino

Languages - Java, C#, C++, MATLAB

Web Development - HTML5/CSS, BootStrap, JSON, WordPress

**Design** - SolidWorks, GIMP / Photoshop, Inkscape

**Environments** - Eclipse, Visual Studio **Dev. Tools** - Git, JIRA, Confluence, Wikis

## **Projects**

**College Mood Meter** - Working in a team of three during Ohio State's second annual hackathon, OHI/O, we built an application to pull tweets from Twitter's API, identify college students, and then determine happiness, stress, and spirit levels through searches for specific keywords. Data for multiple schools were compared and outputted in a static HTML webpage.

**Hackalist.org** - Open source website listing upcoming hackathons open to all students. Utilizes parsing of public JSON API. Currently serving hundreds of students around the world with several contributors to the project through GitHub.

**DailyBitcoiner.com** - Website featuring an online bitcoin-accepting merchant every day with daily postings to social media. Page code generated in self-created C# application for Windows.

**Advanced Energy Vehicle** - Working in a team of fellow students, an electric AEV was modeled through SolidWorks, coded with MATLAB, assembled, and tested on an indoor track with various goals in mind (e.g. speed control and stopping).

**CheapShark Application** - A Windows 8 Metro application coded in C# that pulls JSON data form CheapShark.com, an aggregator of PC game deals from across the web. Currently unreleased.

#### **Work Experience**

### Taazaa Inc.

#### Intern, Web Development and Community Manager

Hudson, Ohio — July 2014 to Present

- Revamped and developed Taazaa's main website (http://www.taazaa.com/) through HTML and CSS on WordPress.
- Worked in an agile SCRUM work environment controlled through JIRA and wiki collaboration.
- Maintained website content, managed communications and social media, and discovered potential new clients and freelancers for future development projects.

# Intern, Mobile Application Development

Hudson, Ohio — Summer 2013

- Participated in the design, development, and debugging of a healthcare-oriented Android application.

#### **Designer Cabinets, Granite and Tile**

#### Web and Community Manager

Bedford Heights, Ohio — June 2014 to Present

- Established and maintained the social media presence of the company, in addition to managing social media advertising.
- Improved website functionality and search engine optimization (SEO).

#### CheapShark

#### Community Manager

CheapShark.com — September 2013 - Present

Managed the social media presence for CheapShark.com, a PC video game deal aggregator. Duties involved posting updates, assisting users, running giveaways, and working to increase the overall awareness of the site.